# Shadrack Ankomahene

ankomaheneshadrack@gmail.com | +233559617959 | linkedin.com/in/shadrack-ankomahene-5a393311a/ | github.com/ankomahene

#### **SUMMARY**

Focused and independent software engineer with 4 years of experience in frontend development designing and building responsive web applications. Proficient with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Angular, and Typescript, with extensive knowledge of UI/UX. I enjoy solving problems and am passionate about learning and development.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### SOFTWARE ENGINEER (CONTIGENT), Morgan Stanley

Feb 2020 - Present

- Working with engineers in the Morgan Stanley API Squad to architect, design, onboard, automate, deploy, create, and manage APIs in the firm.
- Creating a robust and user-friendly interface that helps users to manage and deploy their APIs using Angular, and Typescript
- Improving the performance of the UI by optimizing the number of HTTP requests made by the application and introducing caching.
- Implementing a self-service tool that helps developers in deploying APIs and validating Open API specifications
- Implementing end-to-end testing with cypress
- Improving the test coverage of the codebase from 70% to 95%.
- Improving CI/CD by optimizing project pipelines and running parallel builds to reduce build time.
- Building a usage metrics dashboard that tracks API usage by clients and applications over time.

#### SOFTWARE ENGINEER, Turntabl Ghana Limited

Oct 2019 - Present

- Developed a robust ETL tool, written in python that streams over 7GB of JSON files from the AWS data lake, converts them to Optimised Row Columnar(ORC) files, and uploads them back to another S3 bucket using AWS Batch with EC2 instances. These ORC files were later processed and used to provide personalized suggestions to users in later service usage.
- Managed a small team of three developers on several projects, assigning work and running code reviews.
- Teach a class of 50 new intakes twice every year on topics such as JavaScript, Angular, React, Java, Python, etc.
- Built a Web App for creating polls and surveys

### FRONTEND ENGINEER, FMT

Jan 2018 - Present

- Current Projects: Dronehub, UIDynamik
- Built the frontend of an online store platform for a design and print company.
- Designed and Built a modern and responsive company website for a construction company which is used to showcase their products and services.
- Published an open-source react component library used by hundreds of people right now.

#### **PROJECTS**

## Dronehub

https://dronehub.netlify.app/

**UIDynamik** 

https://uidynamik.netlify.app/

#### **EDUCATION**

**Bachelor of Education**, Computing and Mathematics UNIVERSITY OF CAPE COAST

Aug 2015 - May 2019

#### **SKILLS**

Frontend: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Redux, Next.js, Typescript, Angular, bootstrap, sass/scss, Tailwind.

Backend: Java, Python, Nodejs, Typescript

Databases and storage: Postgres, MySQL, Firebase, MongoDB, Airtable, CouchDB, S3, cloudinary.

CMS: Sanity Studio, Contentful, Strapi

APIs and microservices: REST, GraphQL, Spring Boot

Project Management: Git, Jira, Agile

Others: AWS, Azure, Jenkins, Heroku, Travis CI, GitHub Actions, CI/CD.